MESHIA REED | Software Engineer

As a Software Engineer with 5 years of experience, I have a passion for solving problems and developing creative solutions. My primary specialties include front-end development with an extensive knowledge of back-end languages. My ultimate desire to work in an environment where technical innovation, equity, and inclusivity are vital for business success.

SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, SQL, Mongo, JSON, Typescript, EJS, DTL

Database - PostgreSQL, MongoDB | Other - RESTful Routing, JSON API

Libraries and Frameworks - React (class-based and hooks), Express.js, Django, jQuery, Bootstrap

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant | General Assembly | Remote

May 2022 - Present

- Collaborate with instructors on course material to evaluate student performance and provide recommendations.
- Provide comprehensive academic support and tutorials in both one-to-one and group settings to arouse enthusiasm of students understanding of MERN stack concepts.
- Offer various ways for students to continuously improve software engineering skills throughout their career.

Software Engineer | Bigtincan | Remote

April 2022 - July 2022

- Developed and updated existing components from mockups by the Design Team.
- Wrote unit test to ensure component met all requirements without breaking code for client-side users.
- Merged software changes using Gi and CI/CD pipelines to test and deploy final versions for production.
- Helped QA to test components using Cypress to enhance the user experience.
- Implemented new Theme UI and JavaScript techniques to provide clean code.

Front End Developer | meltmedia | Tempe, AZ

April 2021 – March 2022

- Develop 6 websites implementing new color schemes, policies, components, expanding feature functionality, and refactored code for readability using Sass, CSS3, and HTML.
- Build committed software changes using Jenkins to test and deploy final versions for production.
- Increased time on websites by 37%, by delivering interactive user experience through clean reusable code, cross-browser compatibility, web accessibility, and call-to-action features.
- Discover new software and techniques to maintain clean code for future client services.
- Update training documentation (life cycle and 101 guides); led training sessions for 7 new and current employees, ensuring team members are well-rounded developers.

Front End Developer | Dansons USA | Phoenix, AZ

April 2019 - March 2021

- Provided clean code interfaces from UI design prototypes, while collaborating with various departments to contribute to a 14% increase in incremental revenues in one year.
- Built mobile-friendly user interfaces using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap 4, PHP, and Twig.
- Executed new changes on 4 websites creating an interactive user experience through optimization of media files, cross-browser compatibility, and call-to-action events.
- Designed dynamic pages to enhance workflow for content specialists in-store management systems.

Web Content Specialist (Contract) | Ronin Consulting Group | Phoenix, AZ

October 2018 - March 2019

- Spearheaded the use of a new Search Engine Optimization (SEO) tool increasing product visibility by 27%.
- Enhanced consumer experience by collaborating with sales and marketing teams to identify product inefficiencies.
- Performed keyword research to identify high-traffic search terms and content opportunities.
- Used Google Analytics, Boostability, and Trustpilot to analyze web and social media metrics and measure the impact of communication strategies.

SQL Developer | Ipro Tech | Phoenix, AZ

November 2017 - October 2018

- Diagnosed SQL data for more than 60% of company products to discover inefficiencies in client databases.
- Scripted SQL queries to provided solutions for clients, improve workflow, and file sequence.
- Used in-depth knowledge, stack traces, and log files to eliminate index fragmentations and check for data corruption on 5 out of 8 products.

Junior QA Engineer | Ronin Consulting Group | Phoenix, AZ

December 2016 - November 2017

- Diagnosed and resolved unique problems associated with application software and operating systems.
- Aided in reducing required time for manual testing by 9% for new product builds.

Service Desk Technician | Ronin Consulting Group | Phoenix, AZ

March 2015 - November 2016

Diagnosed, troubleshot, and maintained application availability by providing technical solutions and interacting
with proper settings, which resulted in an 86% ticket closure rate.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

May 2018 - Present

Jotit - Task organization application | MongoDB, Express, React.js, Node.js

- Utilized a MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React.js, Node.js) to build a full-stack application in 2 days. With full create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations hitting all RESTful API calls.
- Created an application with a mobile-first approach and styled using Styled-Components and CSS3 with grid and flexbox layouts.
- Introduced React animation to enhance user experience when interacting with list items.

True Foodie – Application accepts end-user input for menu items | Express, MongoDB, Node.js

- Made RESTful API fetch calls **to** an Express, MongoDB, Node.js backend handling all create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations, and tested all backend routes during development using Postman.
- Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections.
- Implemented ES6 tagged template literals with styled components along CSS3 to provide style and flexbox layout

<u>Tic Tac Toe</u> - Online Classic Board Game | JavaScript, CSS3, HTML5

- Leveraged embedded JavaScript, Vanilla JavaScript, CSS3, HTML5, with partials to organize and display visual aspects.
- Wireframed and planned UI design of application using Sketch and created a database of images using Photoshop.
- Utilized Git control during the production of the application with frequent commits until deployment.
- Tested API routes using Postman to ensure functionality during production.
- Implemented JavaScript methods and functions to utilize an Express, MongoDB, and Node.js backend creating a representational state transfer (REST)ful application program interface(API).

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, 24-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

Scottsdale Community College | Scottsdale, AZ Web Development Certification

October 2016 - May 2018

Northwestern University | Evanston, IL Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Art Theory and Practice

June 2007 - June 2011